<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Edu Gonzalo Almorox</title>
    <link>/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Edu Gonzalo Almorox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Student to teacher ratios in Europe</title>
      <link>/post/student-to-teacher-ratios/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</author>
      <guid>/post/student-to-teacher-ratios/</guid>
      <description>A measure to define the quality of education is the number of students per teacher. In this tidytuesday project I use data from the UNESCO to visualise the differences among European Countries. As it happens with other domains, such as health there are significant differences depending on the type of education considered. The plot is a good example of how to represent different levels of a factor in a faceted ggplot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How should you call your pet ...</title>
      <link>/post/how-should-you-call-your-pet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</author>
      <guid>/post/how-should-you-call-your-pet/</guid>
      <description>… if you live in Seattle? The tidytuesday project from this week can give you some hints in case you feel undecided. I produce a heatmap with geom_tile() to see what are the most common names for pets in Seattle and whether there are some periods during the year that are more popular than others. There are names, such as Lucy, that seem to be everlasting for dogs and cats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women and salaries</title>
      <link>/post/women-and-salaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</author>
      <guid>/post/women-and-salaries/</guid>
      <description>The 8th of March is the International Women’s Day. In this week’s #tidytuesday I use data data from the Bureau of Labor Statistics and the Census Bureau to plot the gender gap in earnings of women workers in the US from 1979 to 2011. I use gganimate() to illustrate this difference in salaries between men and women over time and by age ranges. The gap (i.e. less female salary percent of male salary) increases at older ages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SNCF trains</title>
      <link>/post/tidytuesday-sncf-trains/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</author>
      <guid>/post/tidytuesday-sncf-trains/</guid>
      <description>A good thing from France is the wide network of trains over the whole country. The company in charge of their management is the SNCF which is state-owned . This week the #tidytuesday challenge consisted of plotting information regarding the the trains. The dataset is quite complete and there are several options for the representation. My choice for this plot is to represent the variation over time in the number of lines covered by each station.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhDs in the US</title>
      <link>/post/tidytuesdays-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</author>
      <guid>/post/tidytuesdays-1/</guid>
      <description>Finally I got myself into the #tidytuesday. This project, promoted by R for Data Science, aims to enhance the manipulation and visualisation skills among the R community by the exploratory analysis of a raw new dataset that is posted on a weekly basis. Apart from improving the #RStats skills, the idea of this project is to enable connections amongst the #Rstats community, explore other´s work and get feedback.
The data for this week consisted of sample of PhDs awarded by field in the US.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is this about?</title>
      <link>/post/what-is-this-about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</author>
      <guid>/post/what-is-this-about/</guid>
      <description>After several attempts I am finally deploying a website. This has been a long journey of trial and error where I have two main sources: This post by Allison Presmanes and this video by John Muschelli.
The idea of this website is to contribute to the community and show case studies that may be helpful for some. You are likely to find a bunch of things associated with care homes, ageing and long-term care in England.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>