<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Edu Gonzalo Almorox</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Edu Gonzalo Almorox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Women and salaries</title>
      <link>/post/women-and-salaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</author>
      <guid>/post/women-and-salaries/</guid>
      <description>The 8th of March is the International Women’s Day. In this week’s #tidytuesday I use data data from the Bureau of Labor Statistics and the Census Bureau to plot the gender gap in earnings of women workers in the US from 1979 to 2011. I use gganimate() to illustrate this difference in salaries between men and women over time and by age ranges. The gap (i.e. less female salary percent of male salary) increases at older ages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SNCF trains</title>
      <link>/post/tidytuesday-sncf-trains/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</author>
      <guid>/post/tidytuesday-sncf-trains/</guid>
      <description>A good thing from France is the wide network of trains over the whole country. The company in charge of their management is the SNCF which is state-owned . This week the #tidytuesday challenge consisted of plotting information regarding the the trains. The dataset is quite complete and there are several options for the representation. My choice for this plot is to represent the variation over time in the number of lines covered by each station.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhDs in the US</title>
      <link>/post/tidytuesdays-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</author>
      <guid>/post/tidytuesdays-1/</guid>
      <description>Finally I got myself into the #tidytuesday. This project, promoted by R for Data Science, aims to enhance the manipulation and visualisation skills among the R community by the exploratory analysis of a raw new dataset that is posted on a weekly basis. Apart from improving the #RStats skills, the idea of this project is to enable connections amongst the #Rstats community, explore other´s work and get feedback.
The data for this week consisted of sample of PhDs awarded by field in the US.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>El 2018 en el Congreso español</title>
      <link>/post/congreso-espa%C3%B1ol/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</author>
      <guid>/post/congreso-espa%C3%B1ol/</guid>
      <description>La semana pasada arrancaba el año en el Congreso de los diputados. El 2018 dejó varios momentos que sin duda serán carne de hemeroteca. Entre los episodios con más seguimiento mediático destacaron la aprobación de la primera moción de censura contra un gobierno en democracia o la expulsión la expulsión forzosa de un diputado del hemiciclo por su comportamiento (el segundo de la democracia).
Pero, qué otras cosas caracterizaron la actividad parlamentaria durante 2018?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping the quality of adult social care</title>
      <link>/post/care-homes-england/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</author>
      <guid>/post/care-homes-england/</guid>
      <description>A key element for a health system is the quality of their services. Knowing how good (or bad) health centres are doing may be useful for policy makers to assess their performance and propose improvements. For other services such as residential and nursing care homes, quality is an important aspect to motivate the choice of certain premises over others.
In this post I look at the quality of care homes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animating administrative data</title>
      <link>/post/ageing-in-england/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</author>
      <guid>/post/ageing-in-england/</guid>
      <description>England as other developed countries is ageing. Is this process going to increase, stabilise, decrease …? The Office of National Statistics regularly releases information on population trends. In this post I look at the old-age dependency ratio (OADR) which represents the people aged 65 and over for every 1,000 people aged 16 to 64 years (“traditional working age”).
The process is relatively nice and easy. It consists of three core steps:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is this about?</title>
      <link>/post/what-is-this-about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</author>
      <guid>/post/what-is-this-about/</guid>
      <description>After several attempts I am finally deploying a website. This has been a long journey of trial and error where I have two main sources: This post by Allison Presmanes and this video by John Muschelli.
The idea of this website is to contribute to the community and show case studies that may be helpful for some. You are likely to find a bunch of things associated with care homes, ageing and long-term care in England.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work in progress</title>
      <link>/post/work-in-progress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</author>
      <guid>/post/work-in-progress/</guid>
      <description>These are the working papers of past and ongoing projects
 The role of queuing models in economic evaluation: lessons from an illustrative case study of emergency care Newcastle Health Economics Group working paper series. HEG2015_03 2015 (with Alexandru Lucian Gaianu and Luke Vale)
 The effect of house prices on the long-term care market: Evidence from England 2017 (with Volodymyr Bilotkach, Nils Braakmann and John Wildman)
 Local budgets and care homes quality in England: a duration analysis 2018 (with Nils Braakmann and John Wildman)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/post/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</author>
      <guid>/post/publications/</guid>
      <description>These are publications in peer-reviewed journals
 Decomposing socio-economic inequalities in leisure-time physical inactivity: the case of Spanish children International Journal for Equity in Health. 15:106. 2016 (with Rosa Urbanos)
 Intra-arterial mechanical thrombectomy stent retrievers and aspiration devices in the treatment of acute ischaemic stroke: A systematic review and meta-analysis with trial sequential analysis European Stroke Journal Volume: 2 issue: 4, page(s): 308-318. 2017. (with Darren Flynn, Richard Francis, Kristoffer Halvorsrud, Dawn Craig, Shannon Robalino, Peter McMeekin, Adela Cora, Joyce Balami, Gary A Ford and Phil White)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/post/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</author>
      <guid>/post/projects/</guid>
      <description>Tracking the quality of social care This is a shiny app presenting information referred to care homes in England. It is composed of three main tabs and uses data from the Care Quality Commission.
 Data: Shows information of current active care homes (as to April 2019) on their quality ratings. It enables to track care all quality inspections undertaken in a care home since 2014. number_inspection and total_inspections_category provide information concerning the number of inspections taken in a care home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/page/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</author>
      <guid>/page/cv/</guid>
      <description>Skills Thinking analytically and creatively Provided tailored solutions to complex problems. Experienced in working with big and untidy datasets applying the most advanced analytical techiques. Ability to learn and apply new techniques and approaches.
Communicating Delivered insights from research in different conferences and workshops for expert and non-expert audiences. Taught seminars on quantitative methods at under and postgraduate level. Designed and delivered technical workshops.
Modeling Applied quasi-experimental and statistical techniques for addressing questions of causal inference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/page/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</author>
      <guid>/page/resume/</guid>
      <description>Skills Thinking analytically and creatively Provided tailored solutions to complex problems. Experienced in working with big and untidy datasets applying the most advanced analytical techiques. Ability to learn and apply new techniques and approaches.
Communicating Delivered insights from research in different conferences and workshops for expert and non-expert audiences. Taught seminars on quantitative methods at under and postgraduate level. Designed and delivered technical workshops.
Modeling Applied quasi-experimental and statistical techniques for addressing questions of causal inference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Me in a nutshell....</title>
      <link>/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</author>
      <guid>/page/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a quantitative researcher interested applied economics with an emphasis in health and computational social science. I received my PhD in Economics from Newcastle University.
My research investigates empirical issues in the market for adult long term (social) care in England. I am also involved in projects associated with unhealthy behaviours and tools for open science.
Before joining the Department of Economics, I was a NIHR reserch methods fellow in the Health Economics Group at Newcastle University and prior to that I held several positions as an economics consultant at Funcas and the European Corporate Affairs Office at Banco Santander.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>