<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Edu Gonzalo Almorox</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Edu Gonzalo Almorox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What is this about?</title>
      <link>/post/what-is-this-about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</author>
      <guid>/post/what-is-this-about/</guid>
      <description>After several attempts I am finally deploying a website. This has been a long journey of trial and error where I have two main sources: This post by Allison Presmanes and this video by John Muschelli.
The website is built with R blogdown and Hugo. It is hosted and deployed in netlifly.com. The template is based on the Beautiful theme.
The idea of this blog is to contribute to the community and show case studies that may be helpful for some.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work in progress</title>
      <link>/post/work-in-progress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</author>
      <guid>/post/work-in-progress/</guid>
      <description>These are the working papers that I have worked or I am working on
 The role of queuing models in economic evaluation: lessons from an illustrative case study of emergency care Newcastle Health Economics Group working paper series. HEG2015_03 2015 (with Alexandru Lucian Gaianu and Luke Vale)
 The effect of house prices on the long-term care market: Evidence from England 2017 (with Volodymyr Bilotkach, Nils Braakmann and John Wildman)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/post/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</author>
      <guid>/post/publications/</guid>
      <description>These are publications in *peer-reviewed journals
 Decomposing socio-economic inequalities in leisure-time physical inactivity: the case of Spanish children International Journal for Equity in Health. 15:106. 2016 (with Rosa Urbanos)
 Intra-arterial mechanical thrombectomy stent retrievers and aspiration devices in the treatment of acute ischaemic stroke: A systematic review and meta-analysis with trial sequential analysis European Stroke Journal Volume: 2 issue: 4, page(s): 308-318. 2017. (with Darren Flynn, Richard Francis, Kristoffer Halvorsrud, Dawn Craig, Shannon Robalino, Peter McMeekin, Adela Cora, Joyce Balami, Gary A Ford and Phil White)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>