<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Edu Gonzalo Almorox</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Edu Gonzalo Almorox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping the quality of adult social care</title>
      <link>/post/care-homes-england/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</author>
      <guid>/post/care-homes-england/</guid>
      <description>A key element for a health system is the quality of their services. Knowing how good (or bad) health centres are doing may be useful for policy makers to assess their performance and propose improvements. For other services such as residential and nursing care homes, quality is an important aspect to motivate the choice of certain premises over others.
In this post I look at the quality of care homes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animating administrative data</title>
      <link>/post/ageing-in-england/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</author>
      <guid>/post/ageing-in-england/</guid>
      <description>England as other developed countries is ageing. Is this process going to increase, stabilise, decrease …? The Office of National Statistics regularly releases information on population trends. In this post I look at the old-age dependency ratio (OADR) which represents the people aged 65 and over for every 1,000 people aged 16 to 64 years (“traditional working age”).
The process is relatively nice and easy. It consists of three core steps:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is this about?</title>
      <link>/post/what-is-this-about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</author>
      <guid>/post/what-is-this-about/</guid>
      <description>After several attempts I am finally deploying a website. This has been a long journey of trial and error where I have two main sources: This post by Allison Presmanes and this video by John Muschelli.
The idea of this website is to contribute to the community and show case studies that may be helpful for some. You are likely to find a bunch of things associated with care homes, ageing and long-term care in England.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work in progress</title>
      <link>/post/work-in-progress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</author>
      <guid>/post/work-in-progress/</guid>
      <description>These are the working papers of past and ongoing projects
 The role of queuing models in economic evaluation: lessons from an illustrative case study of emergency care Newcastle Health Economics Group working paper series. HEG2015_03 2015 (with Alexandru Lucian Gaianu and Luke Vale)
 The effect of house prices on the long-term care market: Evidence from England 2017 (with Volodymyr Bilotkach, Nils Braakmann and John Wildman)
 Local budgets and care homes quality in England: a duration analysis 2018 (with Nils Braakmann and John Wildman)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/post/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</author>
      <guid>/post/projects/</guid>
      <description>Coming soon …!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/post/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</author>
      <guid>/post/publications/</guid>
      <description>These are publications in peer-reviewed journals
 Decomposing socio-economic inequalities in leisure-time physical inactivity: the case of Spanish children International Journal for Equity in Health. 15:106. 2016 (with Rosa Urbanos)
 Intra-arterial mechanical thrombectomy stent retrievers and aspiration devices in the treatment of acute ischaemic stroke: A systematic review and meta-analysis with trial sequential analysis European Stroke Journal Volume: 2 issue: 4, page(s): 308-318. 2017. (with Darren Flynn, Richard Francis, Kristoffer Halvorsrud, Dawn Craig, Shannon Robalino, Peter McMeekin, Adela Cora, Joyce Balami, Gary A Ford and Phil White)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>