<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on Edu Gonzalo Almorox</title>
    <link>/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on Edu Gonzalo Almorox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</webMaster>
    
	<atom:link href="/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/page/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</author>
      <guid>/page/cv/</guid>
      <description>Skills Thinking analytically and creatively Provided tailored solutions to complex problems. Experienced in working with big and untidy datasets applying the most advanced analytical techiques. Ability to learn and apply new techniques and approaches.
Communicating Delivered insights from research in different conferences and workshops for expert and non-expert audiences. Taught seminars on quantitative methods at under and postgraduate level. Designed and delivered technical workshops.
Modeling Applied quasi-experimental and statistical techniques for addressing questions of causal inference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Me in a nutshell....</title>
      <link>/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</author>
      <guid>/page/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a quantitative researcher interested applied economics with an emphasis in health and computational social science. I received my PhD in Economics from Newcastle University.
My research investigates empirical issues in the market for adult long term (social) care in England. I am also involved in projects associated with unhealthy behaviours and tools for open science.
Before joining the Department of Economics, I was a NIHR reserch methods fellow in the Health Economics Group at Newcastle University and prior to that I held several positions as an economics consultant at Funcas and the European Corporate Affairs Office at Banco Santander.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>/page/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</author>
      <guid>/page/resume/</guid>
      <description>Skills Thinking analytically and creatively Provided tailored solutions to complex problems. Experienced in working with big and untidy datasets applying the most advanced analytical techiques. Ability to learn and apply new techniques and approaches.
Communicating Delivered insights from research in different conferences and workshops for expert and non-expert audiences. Taught seminars on quantitative methods at under and postgraduate level. Designed and delivered technical workshops.
Modeling Applied quasi-experimental and statistical techniques for addressing questions of causal inference.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>