<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gganimate on Edu Gonzalo Almorox</title>
    <link>/tags/gganimate/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gganimate on Edu Gonzalo Almorox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/gganimate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Women and salaries</title>
      <link>/post/women-and-salaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</author>
      <guid>/post/women-and-salaries/</guid>
      <description>The 8th of March is the International Women’s Day. In this week’s #tidytuesday I use data data from the Bureau of Labor Statistics and the Census Bureau to plot the gender gap in earnings of women workers in the US from 1979 to 2011. I use gganimate() to illustrate this difference in salaries between men and women over time and by age ranges. The gap (i.e. less female salary percent of male salary) increases at older ages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhDs in the US</title>
      <link>/post/tidytuesdays-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</author>
      <guid>/post/tidytuesdays-1/</guid>
      <description>Finally I got myself into the #tidytuesday. This project, promoted by R for Data Science, aims to enhance the manipulation and visualisation skills among the R community by the exploratory analysis of a raw new dataset that is posted on a weekly basis. Apart from improving the #RStats skills, the idea of this project is to enable connections amongst the #Rstats community, explore other´s work and get feedback.
The data for this week consisted of sample of PhDs awarded by field in the US.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animating administrative data</title>
      <link>/post/ageing-in-england/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>eduardogonzaloalmorox@gmail.com (Edu Gonzalo Almorox)</author>
      <guid>/post/ageing-in-england/</guid>
      <description>England as other developed countries is ageing. Is this process going to increase, stabilise, decrease …? The Office of National Statistics regularly releases information on population trends. In this post I look at the old-age dependency ratio (OADR) which represents the people aged 65 and over for every 1,000 people aged 16 to 64 years (“traditional working age”).
The process is relatively nice and easy. It consists of three core steps:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>